Hello everyone. So today we are going to talk about a few things, I think all very interesting
大家好。今天我们要谈论一些事情，我认为都非常有趣。
topics. In particular, we are going to talk about transactions, how in general, how do
交易。具体而言，我们将讨论交易的一般情况，以及如何进行交易。
different computers can agree with each other. And then we are going to talk quite a bit
不同的计算机可以相互协调。然后我们会聊很多。
about networking. So let's start. So if you remember from last time, we discussed about
关于网络。那么我们开始吧。如果你还记得上次的内容，我们讨论了关于网络的一些问题。
retouching the protocols. And protocol is a fundamental concept when two parties are
修改协议。协议是当两方进行交流时的基本概念。
communicating. Because you need a protocol to see how everyone is going to perform the
沟通。因为你需要一个协议来看每个人的表现如何。
communication and how it's going to interpret the communication. And like we discussed last
沟通以及如何解读沟通的方式。就像我们上次讨论的那样。
time, there are two parts of a protocol. It's a syntax, and the syntax is basically described
时间，协议有两个部分。一个是语法，语法基本上是描述了协议的结构和格式。
as a structure, the commands of the communication protocol. And then there is a semantics which
作为一个结构，通信协议的命令。然后还有一个语义。
describes the meaning of the messages, the meaning of the commands. And these are typically
描述了消息的含义，命令的含义。而这些通常是
implemented by state machines. So you send a message, what is a state machine means here
"implemented by state machines" 这里的 "state machines" 是什么意思？
is that you are going in initial state and from initial state, you are going to send
你是指你现在处于初始状态，并且从初始状态开始发送吗？
a message and then you may transition in a state in which you are waiting for a reply.
一条消息，然后你可以进入等待回复的状态。
That's the difference. If you wait for a reply, the reply doesn't come, then you may have
这就是区别。如果你等待回复，但回复没有到来，那么你可能遇到了
experienced a timeout and you are going to go into another state and you are maybe you
经历了超时，你将进入另一个状态，也许你会
are going to resend the original message. Just to give you a sense. And also if you
要重新发送原始消息。只是为了让你有个概念。还有，如果你
want the protocol to be fault tolerant, one way to do it is to store its state, the current
希望协议具备容错性，其中一种方法是存储其状态，即当前状态。
state of the protocol, so that when you are going, when you come back up after the failures,
协议的状态，这样当你离开时，当你在故障后重新启动时，
you know where you left. And here it's a very simple classic example. So this is about,
你知道你把东西放在哪里了。这是一个非常简单的经典例子。所以这是关于...
for instance, when you talk with someone who is by telephone, by phone, you pick up the
例如，当你与一个通过电话进行交谈的人交谈时，你会拿起电话。
phone, you open it and listen for dial tone. Today on the cell phones, there are no longer
电话，你打开它并听取拨号音。如今在手机上，不再有
dial phones, but if you used one of these older phones, you know that it's a dial phone,
拨号电话，但如果你使用过其中一种旧电话，你就知道它是一个拨号电话。
dial tone. And dial tone, meaning that the phone is available, you can dial in the number.
拨号音。拨号音表示电话可用，您可以拨入号码。
If it's busy signals, then you cannot. Well, you can, but nothing will happen. So you dial
如果是忙音，那么你不能拨通。嗯，你可以拨，但是没有任何反应。所以你拨号
a phone number and then you hear the ringing. This means that the other person, the phone
一个电话号码，然后你听到了铃声。这意味着另一个人，电话的
rings to the other person and then colleagues is going to answer hello. And then you are
对方的电话响了，然后同事会接听并说“你好”。然后你就可以开始了。
going to start the conversation. And then typically there is some kind of protocol.
要开始对话了。然后通常会有某种协议。
This is again, describe the protocol. Then typically when you wait for an answer, what
这是再次描述协议。通常当你等待回答时，会发生什么？
do you do? You pause, you don't continue speaking. You ask a question and then you are pausing
你好吗？你停下来了，没有继续说话。你问了一个问题然后停顿了。
or when you want to give the other part of the chance to talk. And then when the conversation
或者当你想给对方一个发言的机会。然后当对话
ends, you say something like bye or see you soon and then you hang up. So this is an example
结束时，你可以说再见或者很快见到你，然后挂断电话。这是一个例子。
of protocol. And we are going to talk about some of the most important protocols in networking.
协议是网络中的一种通信规则。我们将要讨论一些网络中最重要的协议。
Next lecture in particular, we are going to talk about TCP transfer control protocol.
下一堂课，我们将特别讨论TCP传输控制协议。
Any questions? Okay. So again, these are red lines represent basically the communication
有任何问题吗？好的。所以再次强调，这些红线基本上代表着沟通。
exchange of the information between the two parties. The first group of arrows exchange
双方之间的信息交流。第一组箭头进行交换。
represents setting up the connection, setting up the call. You ring and then the other party
表示建立连接，建立通话。你拨号，然后对方接听。
answers. But from that point you can start communicating. Then the second group of arrows
回答。但从那一点开始，你可以开始交流。然后是第二组箭头。
represents the communication after the connection has been established. And the last group,
表示连接建立后的通信。而最后一组，
it's obviously closing the connection. Last two arrows.
这显然是在关闭连接。最后两个箭头。
So now, so fundamentally now we are having an network and we are having different machines.
所以现在，基本上我们有一个网络，我们有不同的机器。
And like we discussed last time, many of the applications are running on different machines.
和我们上次讨论的一样，许多应用程序都在不同的机器上运行。
All these, your client, Facebook client and backend of Facebook is the same application.
所有这些，你的客户端，Facebook的客户端和Facebook的后端都是同一个应用程序。
The backend of Facebook or Google consists of many machines. On Serana queries, there
Facebook或Google的后端由许多机器组成。在Serana查询中，
are a large number of machines which are going to contribute to provide you with the answer.
有很多机器将会为您提供答案。
So these machines somehow needs to communicate, needs to synchronize among themselves. And
所以这些机器需要以某种方式进行通信，彼此需要同步。而且
the biggest challenge here is that it's again, it's like you need to, on a single machine,
这里最大的挑战是，又一次，就像你需要在一台机器上完成。
we have the same problem to synchronize multiple threads. But in the case of a single machine,
我们有同样的问题，需要同步多个线程。但在单台机器的情况下，
we've done that at the end of the day by using this kind of hardware primitives like test
我们最终通过使用这种硬件原语（如测试）来完成了这个任务。
and set, which are atomics, right? Checking a value and setting a value and that operation
和设置，它们是原子操作，对吗？检查一个值并设置一个值，这个操作
is atomic. So if you remember, it's all very, very helpful to build also the higher level
是原子的。所以如果你记得，对于构建更高级别的东西也非常非常有帮助。
of communication, synchronization primitives like PNB and things like that, or locks and
通信的方式，同步原语如PNB等，或者锁和其他类似的东西。
semaphores. The problem in a distributed system, that's the only way to application processes
信号量。在分布式系统中，这是应用程序进程之间唯一的通信方式。
running on different machines can communicate is through sending a receiving message. That's
通过发送和接收消息，不同机器之间可以进行通信。
the only thing you have. And sending and receiving a message is atomic in the sense that typically
你所拥有的唯一东西。发送和接收消息在某种意义上是原子的，通常情况下。
the receiver gets the entire message you send by the sender, you don't get half a message.
接收者会收到发送者发送的完整信息，不会只收到一半的信息。
But you don't have more than that. Anyway, if you can think about this, about what the
但你没有更多的了。不管怎样，如果你能考虑一下，关于什么
abstraction looks like to exchange information between two processes running on different
抽象化看起来像是在不同运行的两个进程之间交换信息
machines, sending and receiving message abstraction is like a mailbox, right? You put a letter,
机器之间发送和接收消息的抽象就像一个邮箱，对吗？你把一封信放进去，
you send a letter, the recipient gets a letter and sends you back, right? So you have a send
您发送一封信，收件人收到信后会回信给您，对吗？所以您有一个发送的动作。
primitive and a receive primitive. That's pretty much what you have. So now let's think
原语和接收原语。这基本上就是你所拥有的。现在让我们思考一下。
about how we are going to use these primitives to build higher level primitives. And one
关于我们如何使用这些基本元素来构建更高级的元素。还有一个问题。
of the most basic primitives is about consensus. So basically what consensus is about is that
最基本的原语之一是关于共识的。所以基本上共识是关于什么的呢，就是
you want multiple nodes, multiple parties to agree on a value, right? So this is what
你想要多个节点、多个参与方对一个值达成一致，对吗？那么这就是你想要的。
consensus means, to agree on something, right? To pick one choice from multiple choices.
共识意味着在某件事上达成一致，对于多个选择中选择一个选项，对吗？
So you need to do this in an environment in which different nodes may fail, stop responding
所以你需要在一个可能出现不同节点故障、停止响应的环境中进行这个操作。
and messages can be lost. And also the message, how long it takes a message to be delivered
并且消息可能会丢失。还有一条消息，需要多长时间才能被送达？
can be unbounded. Okay. So this is a problem, right? And just to simplify the problem, actually,
可以是无界的。好的。所以这是一个问题，对吗？为了简化问题，实际上，
you just think about there are two parties which wants to choose between true and false,
你只需要考虑有两个派别想在真与假之间做出选择。
right? And if they choose the same, have the same choice, they commit, otherwise they abort.
对吗？如果他们选择相同，做出了相同的选择，他们就会执行，否则他们会中止。
Okay. And again, you need to do that in a globally scalable system and the decision
好的。再次强调，你需要在一个全球可扩展的系统中完成这个任务，并且需要做出决策。
shouldn't be forgotten, especially when there is a failure, right? So you need to have some
不应该被遗忘，尤其是在失败的时候，对吧？所以你需要有一些
sort of durability. So here is the example. The example is this general paradox. This
是一种耐久性。所以这里有一个例子。这个例子是一个普遍的悖论。这
This is the one formulation of the problem.
这是问题的一个表述。
To just illustrate the point.
只是为了说明这一点。
So here's assume that you have two generals
所以假设你有两个将军
who want to attack, who must attack the enemy.
谁想要进攻，谁必须进攻敌人。
In this case, the red enemy,
在这种情况下，红色的敌人，
the red castle in the middle.
中间的红色城堡。
Now, if both of these armies on each side
现在，如果双方的军队都在各自的一侧
attack at the same time, they are going to win.
同时发动攻击，他们将会获胜。
If they attack at different times,
如果他们在不同的时间攻击，
they are going to lose.
他们将会失败。
Because the enemy is more powerful than a single army,
因为敌人比单一的军队更强大，
but it's less powerful than two army put together.
但它的力量比两支军队加在一起还要弱。
So as such, in this case, the two armies need,
因此，在这种情况下，两支军队需要...
and the generals of the two armies need to agree
并且两军的将领需要达成一致意见。
when to attack.
什么时候进攻。
Now the biggest problem, and obviously here,
现在最大的问题，显然在这里，
think about all times, you need to send messengers.
想想所有的时候，你需要派遣信使。
But the messenger can be intercepted by the enemy
但是信使可能会被敌人拦截。
because the enemy is in the valley,
因为敌人在山谷中，
so say in this case, between the two armies.
所以在这种情况下，指的是两支军队之间。
Okay?
好的。
And, you know, this is, it was a real similar situation
而且，你知道的，这个情况真的很相似。
like this caster in the history of United States,
就像美国历史上的这位播音员一样，
that was a battle, little big horn when he arrived earlier,
那是一场战斗，小大角山，当他早早到达时，
and he engaged earlier, and I believe he died.
他之前参与了，我相信他已经去世了。
But it's a problem.
但这是个问题。
So the power, you know, what we need to do here
所以，你知道，我们在这里需要做什么。
is to develop a solution in which, you know,
是要开发一个解决方案，你知道的，
the two generals are going to agree on the time
两位将军将就时间达成一致。
when to attack.
什么时候进攻。
Okay? That's a problem.
好吗？那是个问题。
So can you develop such a protocol in an environment
所以你能在一个环境中开发这样的协议吗？
in which the messages can be lost, can be arbitrarily late?
在这种情况下，信息可能会丢失，可能会任意延迟。
It turns out that the answer is no.
原来答案是否定的。
And fundamentally it's, again, say one general say,
而根本上，再次说一句普遍的话，
you know, I want to attack at 11 AM.
你知道吗，我想在上午11点发起攻击。
The other one say, okay, yes, 11 AM works.
另一个人说，好的，是的，上午11点可以。
But then the second one who says that,
但是接着第二个人说道，
how he knows that the first general got his message,
他如何知道第一位将军收到了他的消息？
the confirmation, because if he didn't, right,
确认一下，因为如果他没有的话，对吧，
if he didn't get the confirmation,
如果他没有收到确认信息，
then he's not going to attack, right?
那么他不会发动攻击，对吗？
And the second general will attack alone, right?
第二位将军会独自发动攻击，对吗？
And so forth.
等等。
So I told you that there is already no solution.
所以我告诉你，已经没有解决办法了。
Now I just want you to think a little bit,
现在我只是希望你稍微思考一下，
and here is an example about an instance, right?
这是一个关于实例的例子，对吗？
But can you think about, and can you argue convincingly,
但你能思考吗，你能有说服力地辩论吗？
there is no protocol such that under these conditions,
没有这样的协议，在这些条件下，
in which the messages can be lost
在其中消息可能会丢失的情况下
and can be arbitrarily delayed,
并且可以任意延迟。
the two generals can agree on the time to attack.
两位将军可以就进攻的时间达成一致。
Why don't you take, you know, a few seconds,
为什么不花几秒钟呢，你知道的，
maybe half a minute?
可能半分钟吧？
To think about this problem.
思考这个问题。
And during this time, I'll get some other.
在这段时间里，我会找一些其他的事情做。
(clicking)
Sorry, I am unable to understand or translate clicking sounds. Please provide the text you would like me to translate.
I'm sorry, but I am unable to translate non-Chinese text into Chinese. Could you please provide the text in Chinese that you would like me to translate into English?
Okay, any idea?
好的，有什么想法吗？
Yes, there is always a final message required, Allison,
是的，艾莉森，总是需要一条最后的信息。
answer, there is always a final message required
回答，总是需要一个最终的信息。
to terminate the protocol,
终止协议。
and if that message is delayed or does not arrive,
如果那条消息延迟或者没有送达，
the protocol cannot terminate.
协议无法终止。
(clicking)
Sorry, I am unable to process clicks or any non-textual input. Please provide your text in written form so that I can assist you with the translation.
Okay, yeah, this is a pretty good answer.
好的，是的，这是一个相当不错的回答。
Anyone wants to chime in?
有人想要加入讨论吗？
So the more formal proof is the following.
所以更正式的证明如下。
Assume that the protocol, a protocol exists,
假设存在一个协议。
and assume that the protocol has m messages, right?
并且假设该协议有m条消息，对吗？
Any protocol has to terminate, right?
任何协议都必须终止，对吗？
So it must have a finite number of messages, right?
所以它一定有有限数量的消息，对吗？
Otherwise, if it never terminates,
否则，如果它永远不会终止，
the general by definition will never agree.
将军从定义上来说永远不会同意。
But now think about the last message.
但是现在想想最后一条消息。
I am sending the last message to you, so you want to agree.
我正在给你发送最后一条消息，所以你想要同意。
So I send the message, but that's the last message.
所以我发送了消息，但那是最后一条消息。
And I have no idea whether that message
而且我不知道那条信息是什么意思。
was received by you or it wasn't received by you.
被你收到了还是没有被你收到。
So from my perspective, that message, it's useless.
所以从我的角度来看，那条消息是无用的。
Okay?
好的。
And it shouldn't be needed for the agreement.
并且这不应该是协议所必需的。
Okay?
好的？
So then this means that the protocol
所以这意味着协议
doesn't have a messages.
没有留言。
It's, you know, it's a protocol with m minus 1 messages
这是一个协议，需要发送m-1条消息。
is going to be good enough.
会足够好。
Okay?
好的。
But then you go, so now the protocol
但是然后你走了，所以现在协议是什么？
has m minus 1 messages, right?
有m-1条消息，对吗？
And you kind of go recursively because now m minus 1,
然后你会递归地进行，因为现在是m减1，
the last message doesn't have any value for you.
最后一条消息对你来说没有任何价值。
So it should be m minus 2 messages.
所以应该是m减去2个消息。
Okay?
好的。
So that's kind of the way to think about it.
这就是思考的方式。
But yes, it's, Allison, it's correct.
但是是的，Allison，是正确的。
It's about thinking about the last message.
这是关于思考上一条信息的事情。
Right?
对吗？
So there always the last message for the person
所以，对于这个人来说，总是有最后的消息。
who is going to send it, it's useless
谁会发送它，这没用的。
because they don't know whether it was received or not
因为他们不知道是否已经收到了。
by the other party.
由另一方提供。
So now this is a hard problem, right?
所以现在这是一个难题，对吗？
It's really hard problem.
这是一个非常困难的问题。
And of course, in real life, you can use other things,
当然，在现实生活中，你可以使用其他东西，
but how do we get out of it?
但是我们怎么才能摆脱这个困境呢？
Right?
对吗？
Because we still need different parties to agree
因为我们仍然需要不同的各方达成一致。
to build any useful applications, right?
构建任何有用的应用程序，对吗？
And this is where it comes,
这就是它的来源，
the two-phase commit protocol.
两阶段提交协议。
Because we cannot solve this general problem
因为我们无法解决这个普遍问题。
or general paradox, we solve a related problem.
或者说一般的悖论，我们解决一个相关的问题。
Before going here, any questions so far
在来这之前，有什么问题吗？
about the general paradox, the general problem?
关于“general paradox”，“general problem”的问题？
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So the way to do so is that,
所以做到这一点的方法是，
to get around the problem is that,
解决这个问题的方法是，
and now the challenges of the general paradox,
现在是普遍悖论的挑战。
is that you still have the same problem,
你还是有同样的问题吗？
which you have more than one parties agree on something,
当你有多个方面都同意某件事时，
but you remove that time during which they must agree.
但是你删除了他们必须同意的时间。
So you basically say there are no constraints on time,
所以你的意思是时间没有限制，
they just eventually will happen, eventually will agree.
它们最终会发生，最终会达成一致。
Right?
对吗？
So that's kind of the big deal.
这就是重要的事情。
And this is a two-phase commit protocol.
这是一个两阶段提交协议。
It was developed by Jim Gray, who has huge influences.
它是由具有巨大影响力的吉姆·格雷开发的。
He was the first Berkeley PhD student,
他是伯克利大学的第一位博士生。
computer science PhD in '69,
计算机科学博士，于1969年获得。
and has a huge impact on databases.
并且对数据库产生了巨大的影响。
And many important database breakthroughs
和许多重要的数据库突破
are going back to Jim.
我们要回到吉姆那里。
Unfortunately, he disappeared several years back
很不幸，他几年前就消失了。
while sailing.
在航行时。
So what is a two-phase commit protocol?
两阶段提交协议是什么？
commit protocol is very simple.
提交协议非常简单。
First of all, you do have a persistent storage,
首先，你确实有一个持久存储。
so you can save the state.
所以你可以保存状态。
And then you have two phases,
然后你有两个阶段，
prepare phase and commit phase.
准备阶段和提交阶段。
Also, not all members are equal.
此外，并非所有成员都平等无差。
You have a coordinator and you have a bunch of workers.
你有一个协调员和一群工人。
And the coordinator executes a protocol.
并且协调员执行一个协议。
It basically sends to every worker a message,
它基本上向每个工人发送一条消息，
basically asking to agree with something
基本上是在询问是否同意某件事情。
or not agree.
同意或不同意。
If every worker responds that they agreed,
如果每个工人都回答说他们同意，
the coordinator is going to tell in the commit phase,
协调员将在提交阶段进行说明。
all the workers to commit.
所有的工人都要承诺。
If at least one worker says abort,
如果至少有一个工人说中止，
then all the workers will abort
然后所有的工人都会中止。
and that entire operation is aborted.
并且整个操作被中止。
So again, to take a step back here,
所以，再回到之前的话题，
we want here that another way to think about
我们希望这里有另一种思考方式。
it's all workers, they must execute an operation.
这是所有的工人，他们必须执行一个操作。
Is that all of them execute the operation
这些都执行操作吗？
or none of them execute the operation?
还是它们都不执行这个操作？
In the case of databases, that operation is a transaction.
在数据库的情况下，该操作是一个事务。
So is that all of them execute transaction
所以他们都执行交易吗？
or none of them?
还是一个都不要？
So if all of them are ready,
那么如果他们都准备好了，
are they going to execute the transaction,
他们打算执行这笔交易吗？
say we are ready,
我们准备好了。
we then coordinate, they sent that to coordinator,
我们然后协调，他们把那个发送给协调员。
the coordinator will send back commit.
协调员将会回复提交。
So everyone will commit the transaction.
所以每个人都会执行这个交易。
Otherwise, the coordinator will send abort
否则，协调员将发送中止指令。
and everyone will abort the transaction.
并且每个人都会中止交易。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
And like you'll see,
而且你会看到，
the logs will be fundamental to guarantee
这些日志将是确保的基础。
that this protocol is going to work correctly,
这个协议将会正常工作，
which means that either all workers commit
这意味着要么所有的工人都承诺
or abort the transaction.
或者中止交易。
So again, you have one coordinator in summary,
所以，总结一下，你有一个协调员。
you have N workers,
你有N名工人。
the high level algorithms is the following,
高级算法如下：
the coordinator asks all workers if they can commit.
协调员询问所有工人是否能够承诺。
If all workers reply, yes, we can commit,
如果所有的工人都回答是的，我们可以承诺。
then the coordinator broke us to everyone commit.
然后协调员让我们每个人都承诺。
Otherwise, the coordinator broke us abort
否则，协调员中断了我们的任务。
because there is at least one worker you cannot commit.
因为至少有一名工人你无法承诺。
And the worker just obey these global messages
而工人只是遵守这些全球信息。
where there is commit and abort.
在这里有提交和中止。
That's it.
就这样。
And we use persistent log in order to make sure
我们使用持久性日志来确保
that the protocol will work correctly
协议将正常工作。
when machines fail.
当机器出现故障时。
Now, here we assume that the machine fails
现在，我们假设机器发生故障。
is going to eventually come up,
最终会出现，
look at the log and continue the protocol.
请查看日志并继续执行协议。
But again, we don't put any bound
但是，我们不再设定任何限制。
in terms of the time that this protocol it takes to finish.
就这个协议完成所需的时间而言。
So it's again, there are only two possible votes
所以又是这样，只有两种可能的投票结果。
a worker can make and can do, commit and abort.
一个工人可以制造和完成，也可以放弃和中止。
And commit, it only happens if anonymously
并且承诺，只有在匿名的情况下才会发生。
everyone says commit.
大家都说commit。
So in the previous slide,
在之前的幻灯片中，
in the preparing phase, you remember the preparing phase
在准备阶段，你记得准备阶段。
is a phase in which the coordinator asks every worker
是一个阶段，在这个阶段协调员会询问每个工人。
whether they can commit or they are going to,
无论他们是否能够承诺或者他们是否打算这样做，
they can commit.
他们可以承诺。
If a worker says that it can commit,
如果一个工人说它可以承诺，
then it can do that only if it should commit.
那么只有在必要时才能执行该操作。
And it's also to ensure that can accept the transaction.
并且这也是为了确保能够接受交易。
And this assurance, this vote must be recorded
这个保证，这个投票必须被记录下来。
in the stable log.
在稳定的日志中。
If the worker votes abort, it must guarantee
如果工人投票中止，必须保证
that it will never accept the transaction.
它将永远不会接受这笔交易。
And this is also going to be recorded in the log.
这也将被记录在日志中。
And finishing, it's all the machines have agreed to commit.
最后，所有的机器都同意执行。
Then if all the machines have agreed to commit,
那么如果所有的机器都同意执行，
you record the decisions to commit in the local log.
你将决策记录在本地日志中。
And this is for the coordinator.
这是给协调员的。
And then the coordinator inform every voter to commit.
然后协调员通知每个选民去投票。
Otherwise the coordinator logs the decision
否则，协调员会记录决定。
to abort and send the rest abort to every worker.
中文翻译成英文：to abort and send the rest abort to every worker.
英文翻译成中文：中止并将剩余的中止发送给每个工作人员。
The machines remember the workers from the previous slide,
机器记得上一张幻灯片中的工人们。
they cannot take back its decision.
他们无法撤回他们的决定。
So we are guaranteed that exactly one of this will happen.
所以我们可以确保这两种情况中只会发生一种。
So basically if a worker says,
那么基本上，如果一个工人说，
I can commit this transaction,
我可以执行这个交易。
it cannot let later say I cannot accept the transaction.
它不能让后来的人说我不能接受这笔交易。
And the other way, if the worker says,
而另一种情况是，如果工人说，
I abort this transaction, it cannot later say,
我取消这笔交易，以后不能再说。
oh, I changed my mind, I am committing this transaction.
哦，我改变主意了，我决定进行这笔交易。
Here is another way to look at the algorithms.
这是另一种看待算法的方式。
You have coordinator on the left, worker on the right.
你左边有协调员，右边有工人。
The coordinator sends vote request to all the workers.
协调员向所有工人发送投票请求。
The workers are waiting for this vote request message.
工人们正在等待这个投票请求消息。
If they are ready,
如果他们准备好了，
they are going to send to vote commit to coordinator.
他们打算将投票承诺发送给协调员。
So this means that they can commit.
这意味着他们可以承诺。
Otherwise they send vote abort and are going to abort.
否则他们会发送投票中止并准备中止。
The coordinator collects all the votes.
协调员收集所有的投票。
If all the votes are commit,
如果所有的选票都被提交，
they send the global commit.
他们发送了全球提交。
If at least the vote is abort,
如果至少投票被中止，
then the coordinator sends abort to every other worker.
然后协调员向其他所有工作人员发送中止指令。
And if the worker then receives global commits
然后，如果工人接收到全球提交
and commits, otherwise they abort.
并且提交，否则它们会中止。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
Pretty simple problem, right?
相当简单的问题，对吧？
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体文本。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So now, although despite the fact
所以现在，尽管尽管事实是
that this protocol is simple, it's yeah.
这个协议很简单，是的。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Two questions.
两个问题。
Allison question is that,
艾莉森的问题是什么？
so it's okay if the algorithm stands forever.
所以如果算法永远存在也没关系。
In theory, theoretically it can hang.
理论上，理论上它是可以悬挂的。
It can take forever.
这可能需要很长时间。
I'll show you how later.
我稍后会向你展示如何做。
Actually, let me give you an example.
实际上，让我给你举个例子。
One example in which you can hang forever
一个例子是你可以永远挂着的。
is that a machine fails before getting the global commit.
这是一个在全局提交之前失败的机器吗？
It says commit everything,
它说要提交所有内容。
everyone votes for commit.
大家都投票支持该提案。
And the coordinator is going to send everyone commit.
并且协调员将会发送给每个人提交。
But that machine or the coordinator,
但是那台机器或者协调员，
the coordinator gets, let's do this example.
协调员说，让我们来做这个例子。
The coordinator collects all the votes.
协调员收集所有的投票。
But before, and write the result of the vote.
但在此之前，请先写下投票结果。
But before going,
但在离开之前，
replying with a global message
回复一个全球性的信息
or sending a global message to every worker, it fails.
或者向每个工人发送全球信息，它失败了。
Now we come back,
现在我们回来了，
we're looking at the global storage,
我们正在查看全球存储情况。
is a log that it has,
是一段记录它拥有的。
as a result of the vote, says commit.
由于投票结果，委员会表示。
But before again,
但是在此之前，
can has a chance to send a global commit, fails again.
可以有机会发送一个全球提交，但又失败了。
So this can happen indefinitely, right?
这个可以无限期地发生，对吗？
For the coordinator.
给协调员。
Come up, see the results of the vote.
请上来，看一下投票结果。
But before has a chance to broadcast
但在之前有机会播放之前
the global message to everyone, fails again.
全球向每个人传递的信息再次失败了。
Now, this is unlikely to happen.
现在，这种情况不太可能发生。
So in life, everything is probabilistic, right?
所以在生活中，一切都是有概率的，对吗？
So the probability for this to happen every time
每次发生的概率是多少。
is extremely low,
非常低，
unless there is some persistent bug in the program.
除非程序中存在某些持久性的错误。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
Since messages are unreliable, does the worker...
由于消息不可靠，工人是否...
is the next question from Michael.
下一个问题是来自Michael的。
Since messages are unreliable,
由于消息不可靠，
does a worker keep sending his vote
工人是否持续投票？
until it gets a global procedure?
直到它获得全球程序？
Yes, the workers can do that,
是的，工人们可以做到。
but if the messages are unreliable,
但是如果这些消息不可靠，
the coordinator, like we will see next,
协调员，就像我们接下来会看到的那样，
if the coordinator didn't hear from the worker
如果协调员没有收到工人的消息
for some time, the timeout,
有一段时间，超时了。
then he can declare that the worker
然后他可以宣布工人
who is not able to accept the transaction
谁无法接受这笔交易？
and is going to log the result of the vote as being abort
并且将记录投票结果为中止。
and ask everyone else to abort.
并请其他人中止。
That protocol is still caught.
那个协议仍然被卡住了。
What about when the worker doesn't hear from the coordinator?
当工人没有收到协调员的消息时怎么办？
So, in that particular case,
那么，在那个特定的情况下，
the worker has to wait for the protocol to be correct
工人必须等待协议正确。
because the worker doesn't know whether,
因为工人不知道是否，
especially for a worker,
尤其是对于一名工人来说，
I hear you are talking about a worker
我听说你在谈论一个工人。
who said that it can commit.
谁说它可以承诺呢？
We cannot finish the protocol
我们无法完成这个协议。
until it gets a message from the coordinator
直到它收到协调员的消息。
because it doesn't know what to do.
因为它不知道该怎么做。
It doesn't know whether the vote is commit or abort.
它不知道投票是提交还是中止。
Yeah, so in this case, you have to ask to retransmit.
是的，在这种情况下，你需要请求重新传输。
The coordinator for to retransmit is a global commit
转发的协调员是一个全球性的委员会。
or global abort.
或全球中止。
But it's again, the probability this to happen is very low.
但是，再次发生的概率非常低。
And in practice, it's working.
而在实践中，它是有效的。
It's a very good protocol.
这是一个非常好的协议。
We'll go through a little bit of these questions next.
我们接下来会简要讨论这些问题。
So, here is a failure-free example.
所以，这是一个无失败的例子。
This is a timeline on the horizontal axis.
这是一个水平轴上的时间线。
You have one coordinator, three workers.
你有一个协调员，三个工人。
The coordinator sends vote requests.
协调员发送投票请求。
Then, say every worker sends vote commit,
然后，每个工人都发送投票提交。
and then the coordinator sends global commit.
然后协调者发送全局提交。
Very simple, no failures.
非常简单，没有失败。
Easy.
容易。
Remember, you are discussing in these protocols,
记住，在这些协议中你正在讨论。
you have a state machine.
你有一个状态机。
This is a coordinator state machine.
这是一个协调器状态机。
You are in a unique state, you receive start.
你处于一个独特的状态，你收到了开始。
When you receive start, the next thing
当你收到开始信号时，接下来的事情是什么？
what you are going to do, a coordinator, what it is.
你打算做什么，一个协调员，它是什么。
You send the vote request.
你发送了投票请求。
When you send the vote request,
当你发送投票请求时，
you go to a different state because you need to wait
你去了另一个州是因为你需要等待。
for the votes from the workers.
为了工人的选票。
Okay?
好的。
So, you receive all vote commits, right?
是的，我收到所有的投票提交。
And if you receive all votes commits,
如果你获得所有的选票承诺，
now you are going to go into different,
现在你要进入不同的领域，
you are going to record.
你要录音。
Now, this is the result of the vote is commit.
现在，这是投票结果的提交。
And you send the global commit,
然后你提交全局的更改，
and now you go to the commit, the commit state.
现在你要进行提交，提交状态。
Right?
对吗？
Otherwise, you log the results of the vote as being abort,
否则，你将投票结果记录为“中止”。
and go send a global abort and go into the abort state.
并发送全局中止信号并进入中止状态。
So, while you are in this state,
那么，在你处于这种状态的时候，
if the worker blows a message,
如果工人吹响了一声口哨，
like we discussed earlier,
就像我们之前讨论的那样，
and wants to get,
并且想要得到，
sends a request for the coordinator
发送一个协调员的请求
to resend the decision,
重新发送决定。
the coordinator knows exactly what to send
协调员清楚知道要发送什么。
because based on what state it is, it's commit or abort.
因为根据所处的状态，它要么执行，要么中止。
The workers is similar.
工人们是相似的。
State diagram, state machine.
状态图，状态机。
It's again, it says, "init," I am in it,
又是这样，它显示着“init”，我在其中。
and I'm starting.
我开始了。
In the init,
在初始化中，
I am waiting for receiving the vote request.
我正在等待收到投票请求。
And from here, from the vote request,
从这里开始，从投票请求开始，
I can do two things.
我可以做两件事。
I can say, I want to abort,
我可以说，我想要终止。
case in which I am going directly into the abort state
我直接进入中止状态的情况。
and I'm sending vote abort,
我正在发送投票中止请求，
or I'm going to go to commit.
或者我要去自杀。
And then I'm going to vote to commit.
然后我打算投票支持。
Then I'm going to go to the, in the ready state,
然后我要去准备状态下的地方。
I'm ready to commit.
我准备好了。
And here I'm going to wait for what?
我在这里等待什么呢？
To receive either global abort or global commit.
接收全局中止或全局提交。
I'm going to receive global abort.
我将要接收全球中止。
I'm going to go to abort state.
我要去中止状态。
I'm going to receive a global commit.
我将要接收一个全球性的承诺。
I'm going to go to the commit state.
我要去提交状态。
So, let's see dealing first with worker failures.
所以，让我们首先来看处理工人的失败。
So when I can be affected, if I am the coordinator,
那么，如果我是协调员，我会在什么时候受到影响？
when can I be affected about a failure?
你何时会受到失败的影响？
It's really only when I am waiting for something
只有当我在等待某件事情时，我才会感到真正的焦虑。
with the wait state,
带有等待状态，
because for init, I'm just sending a vote request.
因为初始阶段，我只是发送一个投票请求。
And for commit and abort,
对于commit和abort，
I just send the transition to go to the states
我刚刚发送了去美国的过渡。
by sending a message.
通过发送一条消息。
So here I am, when as a coordinator,
所以在这里，作为一个协调员，
I'm going to be impacted when I'm in the wait state.
当我处于等待状态时，我会受到影响。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
So in wait, if it doesn't receive N votes,
那么，如果它没有获得N票，就会等待。
like I mentioned, you can timeout,
就像我之前提到的，你可以超时。
the coordinator will timeout and send global abort.
协调员将超时并发送全局中止。
This will work perfectly fine.
这将完美地运行。
It will be correct.
这是正确的。
Right?
对吗？
So here is what the examples.
这里是例子。
Coordinator send vote requests,
协调员发送投票请求。
but somehow worker three didn't send vote commit.
但是不知怎么回事，第三个工人没有发送投票确认。
What is the message of the most?
最重要的信息是什么？
So coordinator waits for some time
所以协调员等待一段时间。
to get the commit, the vote from worker three.
获取来自工人三的提交和投票。
But if he doesn't get it, when the timeout expires,
但是如果他不明白，当暂停时间结束时，
he sends global abort to all workers.
他向所有工人发送全局中止指令。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
And that's ended.
这就结束了。
Now let's look at the coordinator failures.
现在让我们来看一下协调器的故障。
When you can be impacted as a worker,
当你作为一名工人时可能受到影响时，
it's again, you are impacted by the failures
这又是你受到失败的影响了。
when you are waiting for something from the party,
当你在等待来自派对的东西时，
which can fail.
可能会失败。
And you are waiting as a worker from coordinators
你是作为协调员的工作人员在等待。
for two messages, vote request, this is in any state,
对于两条消息，投票请求，这适用于任何状态。
and global commit or global abort.
全局提交或全局中止。
So here where you can be affected.
所以这里是你可能受到影响的地方。
So here you need to look at, right?
所以你需要看这里，对吗？
And now this is the answer I gave to the question
现在这是我对这个问题的回答。
of what happens on coordinator fails.
当协调者失败时会发生什么。
So if coordinator fails, worker must block waiting
所以如果协调者失败，工作人员必须阻塞等待。
for the coordinator to recover and send the global message.
协调员恢复并发送全球消息。
Right?
对吗？
Like we discussed before, the worker has no choice
像我们之前讨论的那样，工人没有选择。
but to wait for coordinator.
但是要等待协调员。
Anyway, so let's see as a failure happening in it,
无论如何，让我们看看其中发生的失败。
the coordinators somehow doesn't send the vote requests
协调员不知何故没有发送投票请求。
because it fails before the vote request is sent out.
因为它在投票请求发送之前失败了。
The workers will timeout and they can now send vote abort.
工人们将会超时，他们现在可以发送投票中止。
They can timeout and send vote abort.
他们可以超时并发送投票中止。
Now you are in the ready state.
现在你处于就绪状态。
In the ready state a worker waits for the global messages.
在就绪状态下，工作人员等待全局消息。
Okay, so vote request, and somehow you have vote request,
好的，所以投票请求，而且你不知怎么地也有投票请求。
vote commit, but now the coordinator failed.
投票提交，但是现在协调者失败了。
So now the worker in this case have to wait
所以现在这个案例中的工人必须等待。
for the coordinator to restart
协调员重新启动。
and to send the global abort in this case.
并在这种情况下发送全局中止。
And in this example, and only then they can finish.
在这个例子中，只有这样他们才能完成。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and translate any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
But it's again, the reason for the worker,
但这又是工人的原因，
why the worker needs to wait for the coordinator,
为什么工人需要等待协调员？
it's again, it's very simple
这又是，这非常简单。
because if the worker decides, he says, I can commit,
因为如果工人决定了，他会说，我可以承诺。
he doesn't know what to do
他不知道该怎么办。
because the both choices are valid.
因为这两个选择都是有效的。
He either has to abort or he has to commit.
他要么放弃，要么坚持。
And he must know exactly what has to be done, has to do
他必须清楚知道需要做什么，必须去做。
because he has to be consistent.
因为他必须保持一致。
The decision has to be the same decision
决定必须是相同的决定。
as all the other workers.
和其他所有的工人一样。
So obviously you need to keep the lock in a stable storage.
所以显然你需要将锁放在一个稳定的存储位置。
You need to provide your ability
你需要提供你的能力。
so when the coordinator or say he's going to restart,
那么当协调员或者说他要重新开始时，
he's going to find the state,
他要去找那个州，
the accurate state in the stable storage.
稳定存储中的准确状态。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide the text you would like me to translate.
So that's basically what it is.
那基本上就是这样。
And open recovery, you have the set of rules.
并且在恢复过程中，你需要遵守一套规则。
if the coordinator recovers a board,
如果协调员恢复了一块板子，
if it's in the init, wait or abort state,
如果处于初始化、等待或中止状态，
the coordinator commits,
协调员承诺，
he sees the commit state, right?
他看到了提交的状态，对吗？
So if they have, right?
所以如果他们有的话，对吗？
The worker aborts, if it's in init and abort state,
工人在初始化和中止状态下中止。
and commits in the commit state.
并且在提交状态下进行提交。
And if it's a coordinator,
而且如果它是一个协调员，
if the worker is in ready,
如果工人准备好了，
so he's asking for,
所以他在问，
which is exactly the question we had before,
这正是我们之前提出的问题。
if the worker is in the ready state,
如果工人处于就绪状态，
when it fails and it comes back
当它失败时，它会回来
and you see how it was in the ready state,
你看到它是如何处于就绪状态的，
it has to ask again,
需要再次询问，
the coordinator whether to commit or to abort.
协调员是否决定提交还是中止。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay, so Miles asks the following question,
好的，所以Miles问了以下问题，
if only one global commit message
如果只有一个全局提交消息
from the coordinator to worker fails,
从协调员到工人的传输失败。
we'd be in trouble.
我们会有麻烦的。
Yeah, so let's see what happens.
是的，让我们看看会发生什么。
So assume that the worker,
所以假设这个工人，
so the coordinator said again,
所以协调员又说了一遍，
in the previous example,
在之前的例子中，
we had three workers.
我们有三名工人。
So assume that two messages gets through,
所以假设有两条消息传递成功，
but one global message,
但有一个全球的信息，
global commit message doesn't get through.
全局提交消息无法传递。
Say third worker didn't get it.
第三个工人没明白。
What will happen in that case?
那种情况下会发生什么？
What do you think it should happen?
你认为应该发生什么？
If you design the protocol,
如果你设计这个协议，
implement the protocol,
实施该协议。
what do you do?
你做什么工作？
What do you think we should do?
你认为我们应该做什么？
Third worker blocks for how long?
第三个工人会被阻塞多久？
A certain amount of time,
一定的时间，
or that amount of time expires,
或者时间到期，
what you are going to do.
你打算做什么。
If you are to implement it.
如果你要实施它的话。
So what is the natural thing to do?
那么，自然而然的事情是什么呢？
Maybe it wasn't in the previous diagrams,
也许在之前的图表中没有显示出来。
but that is the natural thing to do.
但那是自然而然的事情。
I don't know as a coordinator,
我不知道作为一个协调员，
decide it, what I'm going to do.
决定吧，我要做什么。
Don't do anything, you are blocked.
不要做任何事，你被屏蔽了。
But what else can you do?
但是你还能做什么呢？
That's something you can do that.
那是你可以做的事情。
No, don't ask it.
不，不要问它。
It's a valid option.
这是一个有效的选择。
Another thing you can do
另外一件你可以做的事情是什么？
is ask against the coordinator.
请问您是反对协调员吗？
That's good action, yes.
这是很好的行动，是的。
You can ask against the coordinator
你可以向协调员提问。
what you decide, that's correct.
你决定的，是正确的。
That's what you'll do
这就是你要做的
if you implement this protocol.
如果你实施这个协议。
Okay, so let's go for,
好的，那么我们开始吧，
have this short discussion.
进行这个简短的讨论。
So why do you need DCBC decision-making?
所以为什么你需要DCBC决策？
Well, you need it because you want
好的，你需要它是因为你想要它。
in four different programs,
在四个不同的程序中，
you want different parts of the program
你想要程序的不同部分。
which run on different machines to agree.
不同机器上运行以达成一致。
A very simple example is that you want
一个非常简单的例子是你想要的。
to replicate the state for durability
复制状态以提高耐久性
on different machines, right?
在不同的机器上，对吗？
So you need, for instance, that's one example.
所以你需要，例如，这是一个例子。
And by the way, a group of machines can come to a decision
顺便说一下，一组机器可以做出决策。
if any one or more of them fail during the process, right?
如果其中任何一个或多个在过程中失败，对吗？
In that particular case, if some process fails,
在那种特殊情况下，如果某个过程失败了，
the other can still come to a decision, right?
另一个人仍然可以做出决定，对吗？
Because they are okay to record,
因为它们可以被记录下来，
say to commit the transaction.
请确认提交交易。
So if the third worker fails,
那么如果第三个工人失败了，
two can still commit the transaction.
两个人仍然可以进行交易。
And maybe the other one, the third worker,
还有可能是另外一个，第三个工人，
when it fails, it comes back and as a coordinator
当它失败时，它会回来并成为一个协调员。
and the coordinator says to commit
协调员说要承诺。
and it's going eventually also to commit the transaction.
并且它最终也会执行该交易。
So, and we said, we discussed that just to reemphasize
所以，我们说，我们讨论这个只是为了再次强调
why 2PC is working and Generals Paradox doesn't,
为什么两阶段提交（2PC）能够工作，而将军悖论却不能？
is because 2PC relaxes the problem
是因为2PC放松了问题。
in that it doesn't require the nodes to commit the transaction
因为它不需要节点提交交易。
and the nodes to agree by a certain time.
并且节点需要在一定时间内达成一致。
They only say that eventually there will be agreement.
他们只是说最终会达成协议。
And it also allows us, that's why, to reboot and continue.
而且这也使我们能够重新启动并继续。
Okay?
好的。
Announcements, homework five is due on Monday.
公告，第五次作业要在星期一之前交。
Midterm pre-grades will close on Sunday
期中预分数将于星期日截止。
by the end of the day.
一天结束时。
Okay.
Sure, I will do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Any more questions about consensus,
有关共识的更多问题吗？
General Paradox and the 2PC protocol?
将“General Paradox and the 2PC protocol?”翻译成中文。
Okay.
Sure. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
If not, we are really going to switch gears now.
如果不是的话，我们现在真的要改变方向了。
And we are going to talk about networking.
我们要谈论的是网络。
Networking is obviously a fundamental part
网络是显然是一个基本的部分。
of the operating system,
操作系统的
especially today where everything is connected.
尤其是在今天，一切都相互连接。
Like we discussed so many times.
就像我们讨论过很多次的那样。
So here are the main concepts you need to keep in mind.
所以这里是你需要记住的主要概念。
First is the network interfaces.
首先是网络接口。
Each of your machines, the machines you are watching now
你现在正在观看的每一台机器
has a network card, some network or a network chip, right?
有一个网络卡，一些网络或者一个网络芯片，对吗？
And that's a chip which communicates with the outside world,
这是一个与外界通信的芯片。
sending physical signals, radio signals and so forth,
发送物理信号、无线电信号等等，
or signals through the wire.
或者通过电线传输的信号。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
These are the physical, you know,
这些是物理的，你知道的，
these are the network cards.
One computer can have multiple network cards
because a computer can communicate multiple ways.
Can you give examples about a few ways
the computer can communicate?
How can your computer communicate with some other computer?
Land, wireless optical copper.
This is good. This is good.
Right? Wireless, wifi, right?
Sounds is good.
It's a good one.
Bluetooth is another one.
Bluetooth, wifi and so forth, right?
Ethernet, you may have heard.
So therefore it's again,
one machine can have multiple cards.
Remember that.
That's network.
Okay.
So, typically each network card is associated two addresses.
One, it's a media access control address or MAC address.
This is a physical address.
And this is burned into the card
by the company which produces these cards.
So when a card was produced,
it comes with a MAC address.
Like we'll see it's 48 bits.
And then there is an IP address,
the internet protocol address.
And this is the address to which, you know,
when we send a packet, operating system sends a packet,
is going to send to one of these IP addresses,
not to the MAC address.
We'll learn more about how they bump to each other.
Okay.
So this is what you have.
MAC address, like I mentioned, is 48 bit unique identifier.
And it's assigned by the card vendor.
IP address used to be 32 bits.
It's assigned by the network administrator
or is dynamically when you connect to the network.
Typically today, almost everyone is dynamically connected.
Your laptop, your phone, when you get an IP address,
that's dynamically allocated to you.
Right, when you connect to wifi, that in a wifi network,
someone is, there is a process
by which you are going to get an IP address.
Without an IP address, you cannot communicate.
[ Silence ]
Right now with IPv6, you have 128 bits. That's the length of the address.
Then you have a connection. The connection happens between two processes.
Now, on one machine, you can have multiple processes.
One machine, you can identify it remotely by its IP address or a MAC address.
But how you are going to identify when you send a message that you want to send to a particular process out of many that are running on the same machine?
That is done using a port number. A port number is a 16-bit identifier.
It has a local scope to an operating system on which the process is running.
Local scope to the machine.
So therefore, a connection is identified by two endpoints.
Each endpoint is identified by an IP address and a port number.
And this is how two processes communicate. This is how your application communicates.
OK.
So you have MAC addresses, which comes with each card.
These are assigned and they cannot be changed.
They are assigned by the vendor, card vendor. You have IP addresses, which in general are assigned dynamically.
And then you have four numbers which are assigned by the operating system to the process.
So now, in order to identify, to send a package to one process, you need to specify both the IP address of the node on which the process runs and the port number of the process.
The port numbers are again used to differentiate between different processes on the same machine.
So what is the main network functionality? The main network functionality is delivery of a packet from between two hosts.
Across the globe. That's a problem.
You know, that's a service it implements.
What do you need to look for?
What are some properties of such service functionality?
Well, you certainly may want to be reliable.
The packet may be lost, may be lost for different reasons.
Can you think about actually some reasons why packets can be lost in the network?
If it's on Wi-Fi, yes. Radio interference and disturbance. Yeah, very good.
Someone turned on the microwave. That definitely can happen.
Cord was not plugged. Yes, I mean.
And we'll see in the packet, even in the wired networks, they can be still lost.
If, for instance, there are too many packets arriving at the routers, more than the router can handle.
So therefore, the buffer the router has is full. Then you have to drop packets.
So that's one. And now this is what we are talking about. Another thing is a flow control.
The flow control is avoid overflowing the receiver buffer.
So say you have a cell phone or whatever, which is all cell phone, which you can get data only at one, say, one megabit per second.
And I am a big server. I can send you packets. I can blast you to 100 megabits per second.
100 times faster than you can receive.
What you are going to do? There is no way you can get at that rate. Many packets will be lost.
So therefore, what you have to do, you need to push back on the sender and tell the sender, don't send that fast.
Just send, say, at one megabit per second.
OK, so this is what you need to do. This is flow control. The receiver pushing back to the server to not send too fast.
Then is a congestion control. The congestion control is avoid overflowing the buffer in the routers.
And we discussed that if the buffer in a router overflows, you lose packets. The packets are dropped.
OK.
So congestion control is making sure that the sender doesn't send too much data so that the router is overwhelmed and these buffers are overflowing.
So packets are lost.
So flow control is slowing down because of the receiver.
Congestion control is slowing down because the routers are in the network. There's a difference.
Now, we have to have right now, today, we have different nodes communicating between themselves.
Each of them executing the protocol. It has a syntax. The syntax will describe what is the packet format.
The types. Right. Right. And the syntax will specify, OK, I get this packet, what I'm going to do with it.
What action I should take.
This means that the two parties have to speak the same language, have to understand and execute the same protocol.
So we need to standardize.
If you want to communicate with someone, they have to run the same protocol.
Right.
If you want to speak with someone else, that person should speak English.
Or maybe another language, both of you know.
OK. So how does this standardization happen?
There are multiple ways. One is there is a standard out there and every software developers follow the standard when it drives the application.
Of course, the other one is basically have only one person, only one company, but I think the entire software, of course, is not desirable and is not realistic.
So that's why in general, you have the standard bodies for the Internet.
The standard bodies is IETF, Internet Engineering Task Force.
And typically the standardization happens for a new protocol, you know, someone's right, a document, we specify the protocol syntax and semantics and send to the other members of this task force requesting for comments.
It's called request for comments.
And after multiple rounds, that can become us can be approved to become a standard.
Become a standard in IETF, you don't need consensus.
Right. It's not like to PC, to face comment.
The majority has to agree. But one thing that always required in IETF is to have running code to demonstrate, which demonstrate that the protocol is feasible.
And typically you are asked for two implementation, different implementation of the same protocol.
OK.
There are also other ways to have de facto standards when some software becomes so popular, it becomes de facto standard.
And others will follow after it, like Linux.
There is no standard body for Linux, but it's a de facto standard.
So everyone follows that standard of writing the application.
OK.
So one thing about and this is a title of this networking section we are doing, we are learning during this class, during this lecture is layering.
So what about layering? What is a problem?
So the layering is a problem here is that think about you write, you know, you want to send a message from your application, from one process to another.
And that is what you know, you write some instructions, high level language, maybe send, receive.
That will be compiled down in machine code and will be executed by the processor.
And now you send it, but then you send it.
Eventually, that information you send, it needs to go all the way to the wire
or all the way to be transformed in a physical signal.
So there are many kind of steps from a send to all the way to that information to be sent on a wire, on radio,
and then to be received, the signal to be received on the other side and to make its way back to the receiving process,
which invokes probably a receive command and ultimately get the data.
And the problem here also is like we discussed, that is there is not only one way to send a signal.
There are many ways you can send the signals. You can use Bluetooth, radio signals, Wi-Fi.
You can use optical networks, optical signals. You can use electrical signals like in wire networks.
So you have many of these things. So you need to organize all of these.
Carrier pigeon. Yes, yes, yes. That's a very good one. You can do that as well.
You can send the information. Right. So this is a problem. Just thinking about application and transmission media.
So how are we going to do it? Like one way to do it.
It's basically for your application, you write your application so that it's able your converters or adapters to send to use every communication media.
Wire fiber optic, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth name it. That's one way to do it. What is the problem with this?
Kind of a lot of work. That's correct, Arison. Right.
Because you have a new application, now you need to implement this application over all this communication media.
And if you if you are the new transmission media, it's even worse. Every application now, if you want to support it,
you need to update the application to work on this over this communication radio radio over this new communication.
Over this new transmission media.
OK. So, yes, a lot of work. So what is the solution?
Encapsulations almost, but encapsulation assume something else. You encapsulate in what?
Layer protocols. Yes, you are talking about layers. That's absolutely correct.
So here is a solution. You add an intermediate layer.
There is a quote, a famous quote, basically saying that any problem in computer science can be solved by adding another level of indirection.
So this is indirection at work. You have an intermediate layer and then intermediate layer provides only one interface to the application.
And all of these applications are going to be written against the same API, the same interface.
And then if I am going to add so basically this is easy, right? I'm going to a new application.
I need to only be worried about only one interface.
To work with. And if you are going to add to add another transmission media, you just need to provide the same interface of the intermediate layer.
And then everything will work.
If a new application is going to if a new application is developed, no need to touch the transmission media part.
If a new transmission media is added, no need to touch existing applications.
Pretty cool, right?
And this has to do with software system modularity.
Right? And the modularity, whatever is going to provide the abstractions, differentiate between the interface and the implementation.
How is the implementation details? That's why when you develop the code, you are going to write functions.
The function provides a signature that's the interface of the function.
Typically the implementation shouldn't matter. You write a function to do sort.
The sorting, the interface looks the same. You provide a list.
And you get out the list order ascending or descending order.
How the implementation, how that is done doesn't matter.
Bubble sort, quick sort, heap sort, whatever.
So this kind of modularity and also it's related with encapsulation, encapsulate the functionality.
It's widely used as a method in computer science. Right? To simplify complex things.
Modularized. Right?
Now, fundamentally, you there is a there is one disadvantage of modularity is great.
Because, again, I can sense I can change the implementation can be a lot of lines of code without anything else in the application to be changed.
However.
This interface is also hide information.
Some information can be very useful.
And without this information, the performance can be impaired.
Let me give you a classic example.
I send a packet to the network.
And the packet doesn't make it is not acknowledge. I expect an acknowledge.
I don't get acknowledge.
What I should do.
Resend it again. Right?
But how aggressively I'm going to resend it and after how long it will depend on how the packet was lost.
It was because the interference like we discussed. I want to resend it immediately.
If it is because the congestion is a network.
Then I want to slow down.
Because if I send the same right, you know, probably the packet was lost because I was sending too fast.
So if I'm just resending and resending and resending.
That more packets are going to be lost.
So in that case, I want to slow down.
So if the interface doesn't allow me to expose this information and today doesn't.
I don't know exactly what to do. So the performance will suffer.
So network is like system modularity, but network modularity is like system modularity.
But it's simplified.
And it's simplified because they have layers. Modules can be connected in any ways.
Layering is connected in only one way. It's basically one layer on top of the other.
One layer can use only the functionality of the layer beneath, which is beneath it.
Right?
So only the two nearby layers are going to interact with each other.
Now you have a bunch of layers. The next question is about, okay, you have a bunch of functionality you need to implement.
Reliability, flow control, congestion control. We discuss about that.
Which layer is going to implement them?
And we are going to learn next time about end-to-end principles, which provide a guiding principle of where to implement certain functionalities.
And then there's a question about where the state is stopped.
So when you have a failure, right, then you can lose a piece of state.
Then you need to recover it. So this kind of stuff, you know, how you are going to think about the state.
state, shared state, in the distributed system.
And we are going to address all of those.
So we have 10 more minutes.
So let's dive in now in other things.
So I said the layering, it's this partition of the system
where a layer relies only on the services from the layer
below it and provides services only to the layers above it.
And the interfaces between layers
abstract away the implementation of a layer which
provides that interface from the layer using that interface.
So a layer can be changed in isolation
without in a transparent manner to the layers above it.
So there are several concepts which
are associated with each layer and we care to answer.
Service, what a layer does, what functionality it provides.
Service interface, how to access a service,
how do you access a service, what is the API,
what is the interface.
And then is a protocol.
The protocol like we discussed in the past
is how the peers, two peers, communicate with each other.
What is the packet format, syntax, what do I do
when I receive a packet.
When I don't receive a packet, when I have a timeout,
there's a semantics.
So it's service, service interface, and protocol.
So this is a network layering.
Initially, it was a standard body, open system
interconnection.
And that declares that there should
be seven layers, physical, data link, network, transport,
session, presentation, and application.
However, the internet protocol, this standard,
it was unsuccessful in the end.
It was overtaken by internet protocol, which was initially
grew as a de facto standard.
And only later, it was an idea, it was created later.
I think nine, 10 years later after IP was designed.
IP and TCP/IP protocol, remember, it was a software,
it was a protocol which was implemented in Unix BSD,
Verical Assistant Distribution.
So you should be very proud about that.
OK?
And with this layer, with the internet protocol,
you have only five layers.
The presentation and session layers
are included in the application layer.
So this you are going to learn about what each layer is doing.
So let's start.
Bottom up, physical layer.
Service moves the information between two systems connected
by a physical link.
The physical link can be wired, optical, or through the air.
The interface specifies how to send and receive bits.
What are the level of voltages?
How you encode one, the ones?
How do you encode zeros?
And the protocol represents actually the coding scheme.
So it's like the interface is basically here,
I am saying about a bit what is a bit.
It's like transition from low to high voltage,
or transition from low to high voltage,
from high to low voltage.
What is the duration of a bit?
How long is sent?
And these are the examples, coaxial cable, optical fiber
link, and so forth.
The next is data link layer.
So by the way, the physical layer
is between two machines which are directly connected.
The data link layer, it's the same,
but here there are multiple machines
which are connected to the same communication media.
Typically, like for instance, the same local area network,
what is called.
All the machines on a Wi-Fi network, right?
If you are connected with the Wi-Fi
to the same base stations, you are on the same network.
And in this case, you need to arbitrate the access
because you have multiple machines sending
on the same communication media.
They can send at the same time, so they can have collisions.
So you need to think about that.
But this is a service data link layer provides.
It can also provide reliable transmission and flow control.
Remember, flow control is what?
Not overflowing the receiver, slowing down
to not overflow the receiver.
The interface is sent frames.
So here are the packets.
Initially, with physical layer, you send bits.
Here you aggregate the bits into frames.
And you send frames.
Each frame has a header.
And the header will have this MAC address, as you'll see.
Finally, you have the protocols.
It is media access protocol to arbitrate access.
And there are many implementations.
We are going to briefly talk about that.
So here is what you have.
You have a frame.
We have a frame header.
The frame header has a MAC destination and source address.
And then they are converted as a lower level
in bits, which are sent on the wire.
You see?
OK.
So you see that you have the counterpoint.
You have the instantiation of the layers at both peers,
at both endpoints.
OK.
So now, you can actually-- you can look about your--
on your machines.
And if you are curious about this physical address
or the MAC address, you can easily find those.
And as well as the IP addresses.
But this is what-- if you do if config in Linux or IP config
in your Windows machine, then you
are going to get these physical addresses or Ethernet adapter
and so forth.
These are the MAC addresses.
OK?
So like I mentioned, a group of machines
which are on the same communication media,
they are called form a LAN, Local Area Network.
And these are the examples.
Computers in your home, Starbucks, wireless Starbucks,
and Starbucks and so forth.
But the most important thing here
is that when you send a frame on a LAN,
that can reach any other machine on the same LAN.
So it's a-- generally, it's a broadcast media.
It's like we are in a room or on this webinar.
I'm saying something.
Everyone else will hear me.
OK?
Now, how do you know?
How does it know?
Because everyone will get the same frame.
How does it know the recipient, the intended recipient
of the frame to get the frame and others not get the frame?
It's because of MAC address.
When the sender sends a frame, it's a frame header.
It puts the MAC address of the recipient.
In this case, it's B. So now, yes, the frame
is going to be forwarded to everyone.
But only B is going to look at the header
and is going to see that it's addressed to itself
and is going to pass the frame to the next layer.
The second, the C, if a computer looks at the frame
and it doesn't recognize its MAC address, it drops it.
OK?
Now, things are more complicated.
Even for a LAN, there are switches and so forth.
And this is what we are going to continue
to discuss next lecture.
And with that, stopping here, please,
if you have any other questions, let me know on Piazza
or send an email.
And I'll see you all on next Tuesday.
Good luck with the homework.
Bye.